About me

Adviser/Influencer profile, with over 10 years of experience in Support Services and IT roles. I have honed advanced critical thinking and problem-solving skills, allowing me for an efficient and seamless adaptation to new environments. My background encompasses Support services, data analysis, Access administration, and Project Management. Currently, I am actively involved in global support projects related to Celergo Payroll Processing, including Data Integration Services, Process Model, Methodology, SLAs, and RCA analysis. And familiarized with Power BI reporting..

I am an enthusiast of blockchain, IoT, and Big Data. Captivated by their revolutionary potential to reshape industries and unlock unprecedented possibilities.

Professional Experiences

Global Service Support Representative at ADP - Automatic Data Processing

March, 2021 - Present

SME in Global Support for the EMEA Region team, working with an iterative and incremental approach to project management, with a focus on collaboration, flexibility, and continuous improvement of Celergo Payroll Product.

I am working on different projects/activities related to Celergo Payroll: Service Catalog, Scope definition, Projects piloting for new enhancements/Features/Portals. I am providing support services, mostly in Escalations cases and ensuring adherence to SLA timelines. Additionally, I play a key role in data integration initiatives, where I am responsible for errors monitoring and RCA analysis.

Within this role, I am leveraging my knowledge in frontend and backend systems, to conduct RCA and thorough investigations to identify and address support/data-related issues. I am performing data analysis and modeling, utilizing analytical techniques to extract insights and reports - Central BI.

Communicating findings, Documentation publication and recommendations to stakeholders. I am collaborating in cross-functional teams, providing System configuration training, assisting Knowledge Transfer and Investigating the Transition to Service completion.

IT Support Analyst - T2 at Computacenter (Airbus)

July, 2014 - July, 2020

My role as T2 was focused on Providing Support to L1 Analysts and covering Escalations and High priority SRs for Airbus Account Admin/VIP users, managing access requests, and resolving errors related to Microsoft Office, Network cases, Active Directory, and SAP transactions errors reports. I am skilled in analyzing and troubleshooting technical issues, documenting solutions. My proficiency in these areas has enabled me to be in collaboration with Account Management, Quality and Training teams.

IT Support Analyst at Computacenter (Air Liquide)

April 2013 - July 2014

During my time As an IT Analyst, I possessed strong technical support skills with specialization in incident resolution, backlog management, access authentication, and Microsoft Office support. I excelled in providing customer support through various channels like chat, phone, and email. Multilingual Support for EN, SP, and FR speakers. Additionally, I was familiar with ticketing systems and user Portals.

Abdel Chafii

Global Service Support Representative at ADP

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ab delchafii/ abdel.chafii@outlook.com Barcelona (08014) Spain (+34) 662118064

Skills & Knowledge

ADP HR systems - WFN

Database Systems: Oracle, Workday, Successfactors

Microsoft Dynamics CRM

Power BI

Active Directory

Ticketing Systems: Jira Service Management, Siebel, Remedy

Packet Tracer

Networking

Data Integration

Admin Console Portals

Sharepoint & Confluence

Basic SAP skills

Microsoft Office - Excel

HTML & CSS

Technical & Functional skills

Booking/Support Team Agent at Avis Budget Group International

March, 2021 - Present

Booking Agent for Renet CAR Service Desk, my responsibilities included handling bookings and Cards sale while ensuring compliance with relevant legislation by countries. I also provided support to customers by addressing queries and resolving issues related to their bookings or loyalty program.

Education

Law from Human Science Hassan II University - Casablanca 1998 - 2000 Master Not completed

Hostelry from ISTA - OFPPT 2000 - 2002

Languages

English, French, Spanish, Catalan and Arabic

Courses & Certifications

ADP - Celergo Learning Path

Data Integration Fundamentals

Oracle Data Integrator (ODI) 12c Developer Course

AWS Cloud Practitioner Essentials

Cybersecurity Essentials

Introduction to Packet Tracer - Cisco

Cloud Computing

Chat GPT cOURSES

NDG Linux Essentials

Oracle Fundamentals